Ogden Family Papers, 1729-1935 Ms 4
Archivists' Toolkit
Ogden Family Papers, 1729-1935
Ms 4
Archivists' Toolkit
0.75 Linear feet (1 box, 240 items, 1 oversize item)
This collection contains papers from the Ogden family of Fairfield, CT including legal and financial papers, military papers and recipes.
Ogden family
Conditions Governing Access note
There are no restrictions on access to this collection.
Custodial History note
Sixteen items and one account book were given by the Stratfield Historical Society (donated to them by Mr. and Mrs. Feduick). Seventy-nine papers, mostly Hezekiah Ogden, were donated by Grace V. Bulkley in September 1984 (L84.52).
Biographical/Historical note
Richard Ogden settled in Fairfield, CT around 1650. He had two sons, Richard (c. 1655-1697) and David (c. 1668-1715) who also lived in Fairfield. The papers of their heirs comprise the bulk of this collection, including many items of Hezekiah Ogden (1755-1844), who was a military and community leader. The Fairfield Museum and History Center owns the Ogden House where David Ogden (1727-1755) loved. Genealogy charts are available in the collection.
Scope and Contents note
This collection is in one box consisting of legal and financial papers, genealogy, letters, mas and military papers. Documents marked "F" are from the Feduick collection and those marked "B" are from the Bulkley collection. The materials in Folders A through D are filed in alphabetical order, except for the deeds which are chronologically arranged.
Ogden, Hezekiah, 1775-1844; Farms--Connecticut--Fairfield--Maps.; Formulas, recipes, etc.; Military orders; Promissory notes--Connecticut--Fairfield County.; Real property--Connecticut--Fairfield County--Maps.; Real property--Connecticut--Fairfield County.; Receipts (financial records); Writs--Connecticut.
- Bills and Promissory Notes, 1771-1854; Folder A; 76 items
  - Bills and bills receipted, 1771-1854; 65 items
    - From Brooks & Stratton to Wm. Bradley, 1848
    - From Jane Ogden to John Hide, 1792
    - From Reuben Beers to Abigail Ogden, 1783
    - From Hubbell, collector for state tax to Abigail Ogden, 1784
    - From Albee Ogden to John Hull, 1791
    - From Samuel Bradley to David Ogden, 1828
    - From Wm. B. Nash to David Ogden, 1829
    - From David W. Jones to George Ogden, n.d.
    - From Elijah Abel to Jonathan Ogden, 1771-1773
    - From Israel Bibbins to Jonathan Ogden, 1793, 1796, 1800, 1801; 4 items
    - From Samuel Penfield to Jonathan Ogden, 1768-1775
    - From Gershom Bulkley to Hezekiah Ogden, 1785
    - From Wm. R. Chapman to Hezekiah Ogden, 1826
    - From John Hazard to Hezekiah Ogden, 1774
    - From Jesse Lyon to Hezekiah Ogden, 1824
    - From William Nichols to Hezekiah Ogden, 1831
    - From John P. Patterson to Hezekiah Ogden, 1822
    - From J. and A. B. Adams to Hezekiah Ogden, 1853
    - From A. D. Baldwin to Hezekiah Ogden, 1840, 1850; 2 items
    - From H. Banks to Hezekiah Ogden, 1857
    - From Wm. H. Bibbins to Hezekiah Ogden, 1849
    - From R. Blakeman to Hezekiah Ogden, 1850
    - From Otis Brewer to Hezekiah Ogden, 1848-1854; 3 items
    - From Lewis Burr to Hezekiah Ogden, 1846
    - From G. B. Guyer to Hezekiah Ogden, 1853
    - From Claudius B. Hall to Hezekiah Ogden, 1845, 1846; 2 items
    - From Wm. A. Howell to Hezekiah Ogden, 1850
    - From A. L. Hull to Hezekiah Ogden, 1849
    - From Pike and Sturges to Hezekiah Ogden, 1843, 1845, n.d.; 8 items
    - From L. Sanford to Hezekiah Ogden, 1853
    - From Selleck Sherman to Hezekiah Ogden, 1841
    - From J. M. Smith to Hezekiah Ogden, 1850
    - From Staples & Adams Co. to Hezekiah Ogden, 1849
    - From Staples Sanford Co. to Hezekiah Ogden, n.d.
    - From Chas. S. Thorp to Hezekiah Ogden, 1844, 1945, n.d.; 6 items
    - Miscellaneous, 11 items
  - Promissory notes, 1768-1801; 11 items
    - From Jonathan Ogden, 2 items
    - To Hezekiah Ogden, 9 items
- Deeds, 1729-1816; Folder B; 21 items
  - From Joseph Ogden to David Ogden and Benjamin Sherwood, 1729-1730
  - From Joseph and Ann Ogden to John Hide, Jr., 1734
  - From David Ogden to John Bradley, 1752
  - From David Ogden to John and Abigail Hide, 1769
  - From Samuel Rowland, Jr. to Hezekiah Ogden, 1774
  - From Hezekiah Ogden to Hezekiah Ogden, Jr., 1800
  - From Hezekiah Ogden to Hezekiah Ogden, Jr., 1801
  - From Sarah Thorp to Hezekiah Ogden, 1803
  - From Ebenezer Jessup and Jonathan Ogden to Abigail Hide, 1804
  - From John Blackman to Hezekiah Ogden, Jr., 1805
  - From Jonathan Ogden to Hezekiah Ogden, Jr., 1805
  - From Jonathan Ogden to Hezekiah Ogden, Jr., 1807
  - From George Burr to Hezekiah Ogden, Jr., 1807
  - From Justine and Abigail Whitlock to Hezekiah Ogden, Jr., 1807
  - From Abigail Jennings to Hezekiah Ogden, Jr., 1809
  - From Thomas Staples to Hezekiah Ogden, 1810
  - From Moses Ogden to Timothy Banks (lease), 1811
  - From George Burr to Hezekiah Ogden, Jr., 1812
  - From Hull and Eunice Murwin to Hezekiah Ogden, Jr., 1815
  - From Hull Murwin to Hezekiah Ogden, Jr., 1815
  - From Hull and Eunice Murwin and Urania Ogden to Hezekiah Ogden, Jr., 1816
- Deeds, 1818-1847; Folder C; 20 items
  - From Joseph Gorman to Hezekiah Ogden, 1818; 2 items
  - From Samuel Banks to Hezekiah Ogden, 1819
  - From John Ogden to Gershom Bradley, 1820
  - From Nathan Perry to Hezekiah Ogden, 1821, 1823; 2 items
  - From Daniel Wakeman to Hezekiah Ogden, 1824
  - From Increase and Deborah Bradley to Samuel and Hezekiah Ogden, 1825
  - From Daniel Wakeman to Hezekiah Ogden, 1827
  - From Samuel Sturges to Hezekiah Ogden, 1830
  - From Giles Bunnell to Hezekiah Ogden, 1831
  - From David Sherwood to Hezekiah Ogden, 1831, 1834; 3 items
  - From Giles Bunnell to Hezekiah Ogden, 1835
  - From David Coley and Daniel Burr, 1835
  - From Uriah and David Burr to Hezekiah Ogden, 1840
  - From Cyrus Sherwood to Sally and Angeline Ogden, 1847
  - From Daniel Sturges to Hezekiah Ogden (copy), 1768
  - From John Sturges to Hezekiah Ogden (copy), 1768, 1772
- Estate and Probate Papers, 1775-1854; Folder D; 41 items
  - Abigail Ogden, 1783-1784; 4 items
  - Betsey Ogden, 1894
  - David Ogden, 1775-1778; 7 items
  - David Ogden, 1828-1829; 10 items
  - Hezekiah Ogden, n.d.; 3 items
  - Jonathan Ogden, 1782, 1807; 2 items
  - Mary Ogden, 1783
  - Moses Ogden, 1827
  - Sally Lyon, 1854
  - John Ogden (photocopy), 1785
- Legal Papers and Genealogy, Folder E; 22 items
  - Animal pound law extract to Hezekiah Ogden, 1836
  - Abigail Ogden's certificate for wood and board, 1776
  - Greenfield's new meeting house pew places. On the reverse side is military drill., 1761
  - Land and crop agreements of Hezekiah Ogden, 1824, 1838; 2 items
  - Contracts re: Hezekiah's future estate, 1816; 2 items
  - School meeting account, Hezekiah Ogden, moderator, 1840
  - Tax list of 1863
  - Miscellaneous accounts, 3 items
  - Writ, Renel Thorp vs. John Ogden, 1772
  - Writ, David and Nathan Bradley vs. Jonathan Ogden, 1773
  - Writ, Job Bertram vs. John Ogden, 1773
  - Writ, John Hide vs. Samuel Ogden, 1773
  - Writ, Isaac Godfree vs. Samuel Ogden, 1773
  - Writ, Thomas Hill vs. Samuel Ogden, 1774
  - Writ, Hezekiah Ogden vs. Josiah Lacey, 1774
  - Writ, Zalmon Bulkley vs. Jonathan Ogden, 1789
  - Genealogy of Burr and Nabby Ogden, 1818
- Letters and Military Papers, 1782-1836; Folder F; 22 items
  - Letters to:
    - Hezekiah Ogden from David Burr, 1812
    - Hezekiah Ogden from A. Bronson, 1823
    - Hezekiah Ogden from Selleck Sherman, 1832
    - Hezekiah Ogden from George Peck, 1836
    - Jonathan Ogden from Eliphalet Hull, 1806
    - John Squire from Joseph Ogden, 1784
    - A. Sherwood from M. A. Sherwood, n.d.
  - Military papers and orders
    - Sturges Ogden et al. military parole, 1782
    - Sturges Ogden military discharge, 1794
    - Walter Jennings' military exemption, 1833
    - Roll book, n.d.
    - Hezekiah Ogden's papers and certificates, 1827-1833; 8 items
    - Gilbert Wakeman, 1832
    - Spicer Davis, 1825
    - Joel Gould, n.d.; 2 items
- Maps, Folder G; 2 items
  - Mrs. Ogden's lot, back side of Mill Hill, n.d.
  - Unidentified
- George Ogden's Account Book, 1837-1871; Folder H
- School Papers and Exercise Book, 2 items
- Ogden House pamphlet for the Connecticut Tercentenary with viewing instructions, 1935; Folder J
- Recipes from Newspapers, 1902, n.d.; Folder K; 43 items
- 3 Recipe Books and Handwritten Recipes, 1883, 1890, n.d.; Folder L; 17 items
- A map of David Ogden's estate distribution of farm land and houses, Gideon Welles, surveyor., 20 April 1769 (Oversize Manuscript Box)